Guide to the Stanford Quad Photographs
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford Quad photographs
1948-1953
1951-1952
PC0085
Stanford Quad.
3.5 Linear feet
Photographic negatives and some prints of images for the STANFORD QUAD, the student yearbook. Most of the images are of individual students (club officers, dorm officials, prominent students, etc.); other subjects include student groups, athletics, and social life. Of note among the student groups are Hammer and Coffin, Institute for International Relations, and Ram's Head.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The materials are open for research.
Description of the Collection
This collection consists of photographic negatives and some prints of images for the Stanford Quad, the student yearbook. Most of the images are of individual students (club officers, dorm officials, prominent students, etc.) Although only the person's head was used for the Quad in many cases, the images themselves contain more information. Other subjects include student groups, athletics, and social life. Of note among the student groups are Hammer and Coffin, Institute for International Relations, and Ram's Head.
The prints were separated from the negatives and are housed in box 1 in a subject arrangement. Not all negatives had prints. The negatives are arranged by year and then negative number. This guide includes an itemized listing of the negatives. The "title" for each negative consists of the subject, the Quad category (activities, senior prominent, schools, etc.), and often the photographer or his/her initials. This list was generated from database; please consult the reference desk for access to the database.
Access Terms
Associated Students of Stanford University. Institute of International Relations.; Hammer and Coffin Society (Stanford, Calif.); Ram's Head (Stanford, Calif.); Stanford Quad.; Photonegatives; Photoprints.
Collection Contents
- Photographs
  - Prints (4x5)
    - 1948-50 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Athletics, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Groups 1951, A (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Groups 1951, C-D (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Groups 1951, F-G (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Groups 1951, Hammer and Coffin (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Groups 1951, Institute for International Relations (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Groups 1951, K-O (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Groups 1951, P-Q (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Groups 1951, Ram's Head (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Groups 1951, S (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Groups 1951, V-Y (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Individuals--Men, 1951: A (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Individuals--Men, 1951: Ba--Be (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Individuals--Men, 1951: Bi--Bu (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Individuals--Men, 1951: C (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Individuals--Men, 1951: D (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Individuals--Men, 1951: E--F (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Individuals--Men, 1951: G (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Individuals--Men, 1951: H (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Individuals--Men, 1951: I--J (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Individuals--Men, 1951: K (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Individuals--Men, 1951: L (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Individuals--Men, 1951: Mc (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Individuals--Men, 1951: M (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Individuals--Men, 1951: N--0 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Individuals--Men, 1951: P--R (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Individuals--Men, 1951: S--T (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Individuals--Men, 1951: W--Y (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Individuals--Women, 1951: A--B (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Individuals--Women, 1951: C (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Individuals--Women, 1951: D--E (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Individuals--Women, 1951: F--G (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Individuals--Women, 1951: H--I (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Individuals--Women, 1951: J--L (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Individuals--Women, 1951: M--N (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Individuals--Women, 1951: P (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Individuals--Women, 1951: T (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Individuals--Women, 1951: S (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Individuals--Women, 1951: T--V (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Individuals--Women, 1951: W (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Social life, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Individuals--Men, 1952: A--C (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Individuals--Men, 1952: D--F (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Individuals--Men, 1952: G--H (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Individuals--Men, 1952: I--M (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Individuals--Men, 1952: O--T (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Individuals--Men, 1952: V--W (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Individuals--Women, 1952: A--B (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Individuals--Women, 1952: C--E (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Individuals--Women, 1952: F--G (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Individuals--Women, 1952: H--M (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Individuals--Women, 1952: P--S (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Individuals--Women, 1952: V--Y (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - 1953 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Miscellaneous and undated (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Negatives (4x5)
    - 1948-1950 (Box 2)
    - #8-553A, 1951 (Box 2)
    - #554A-1403, 1951 (Box 3)
    - #1404-2779, 1951 (Box 4)
    - #1-1697, 1952 (Box 5)
    - #2323-3006, 1952 (Box 6)
    - Unumbered, 1952 (Box 6)
    - 1953 (Box 6)
    - Unidentified (Box 6)
    - Damaged negatives (Box 7)